His story became a legend. His adventure is one you'll never forget.
Balto is a family, animation, adventure film directed by Simon Wells.
An outcast half-wolf risks his life to prevent a deadly
epidemic from ravaging Nome, Alaska.
Balto (voice), played by Kevin Bacon.
Boris the Goose (voice), played by Bob Hoskins.
Jenna (voice), played by Bridget Fonda.
Steele the Sled Dog (voice), played by Jim Cummings.
Muk and Luk (voice), played by Phil Collins.
Young Rosy (voice), played by Juliette Brewer.
Balto is a 1995 animated adventure film directed by Simon Wells, produced by
Amblin Entertainment, and distributed by Universal Pictures.
It is loosely based on the true story of the dog Balto who helped save
children infected with diphtheria in the 1925 serum run to Nome.
The film stars voice actors Kevin Bacon, Bridget
Fonda, Phil Collins, and Bob Hoskins.
Though primarily an animated film, it uses a live-action framing device that takes place in New York
City's Central Park and features Miriam Margolyes as an older version of one of the children.
This is the third and final film to be produced by Steven Spielberg's
Amblimation animation studio, before the studio's closure in 1997.
Released theatrically in the United States on December 22, 1995, the film was a financial failure due to being overshadowed by the release of Toy Story, but
its subsequent sales on home video led to two direct-to-video sequels: Balto II: Wolf Quest (2002) and Balto III: Wings of Change (2004).
The film explores themes of wolf, pet, cartoon, villain, dog-sledding race.